<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="https://tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://cwrc.ca/templates/css/tei.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Sample Document Title</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<p/>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc sameAs="http://www.cwrc.ca">
				<p>Created from original research by members of CWRC/CSÉC unless
					otherwise noted.</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<xenoData><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:as="http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#" xmlns:cwrc="http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:geo="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" xmlns:oa="http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:fabio="https://purl.org/spar/fabio#" xmlns:bf="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#" xmlns:cito="https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#" xmlns:org="http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"/></xenoData></teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<pb facs="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kmabennett/LEAF/refs/heads/main/9-England-Ort-1.jpg"/>
			<div>
				<head>                                              ENGLAND</head>
				<p>The whole Ile of Albion called aſo Britannie beeing the greateſt Ile of this parte of the world, is at this day by two ſeueral names called England and Scotland, becauſe it contayneth thoſe two kingdomes. The Meridional greateſt &amp; beſt parte thereof is called England of Engliſhmen (ſomtyme a people of Germanie) whoſ offpring doth ſtil poſſeſſe the ſame vnder their owne King. It contayneth together with the country of wales, 52 Shyres, 29 Cities and 25 Biſhoprykes. On the eaſt ſyde it hath the Germaine Ocean, On the weſt the Iriſh ſea. On the ſouth the narrow ſeas which deuyde it from France. And on the north it is ſeperated from Scotland by the riuer of (Tvvede) &amp; the (Cheuiot) hilles.It aboundeth chiefly in cattel, for which cauſe the inhabitants are more giuen to graſing then to tillage of the ground, deſyring rather than paſture then corne land. This region is very temperate, and withour great extremitie of cold. The ſoile is exceeding frutefull, howbeit it yeildeth not wyne. There are many hilles, which beeing without trees do yeild a kynde of ſhorte and ſweete gras for the beſt nowriſhing of ſheepe, which are heere in all aboundance, and whoſe fyne fleeces do excel thoſe of other countries, which is cauſed either by the temperature of the ayre, or the goodnes of the paſture. This fyne engliſh wooll, may wel be calleth the Golden fleece, for that thereby ſo great plenty of gold and ſiluer from ſo many &amp; ſo remote regions of the world is brought into this Realme. Here are alſo great ſtore of mynes of Tinne, Lead, &amp; Iron, as alſo of Copper, neither are the mynes voyd of Gold and Siluer. In brief En-gland aboundeth with plenty of all ſortes of vi()uals, &amp; is furniſhed with all ſtore of thinges neceſſary for the vſe of man.</p></div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>